Rahul Ray

Cathodic Protection Technologist NACE CP-3

Contact

Address

870 Rajdanga Main; Plot No. EC-84;

Kolkata, West Bengal,India, 700107

Phone

- +971-527115219
- +91-9903266699

E-mail

rahulray.mail@gmail.com

LinkedIn

linkedin.com/in/rahul-ray-02b0a28b

Skills

Cost Management

Excellent

Client interaction

Excellent

Designing

Excellent

Project Documentation

Excellent

I am an experienced Project Engineer/Manager with 7 years' experience and a demonstrated history of working in the Cathodic Protection industry. Skilled in cross country pipeline, plant pipings, underground, above ground storage tanks, well casings, vessels Cathodic Protection, design, commissioning. Strong engineering professional with a Bachelor of Technology (B.Tech.) focused in Electrical Engineering from St. Thomas College Of Engineering & Technology, Kolkata, India. Successfully completed NACE Cathodic Protection Technologist Course (CP3) and an active member of NACE.

Work History

2020-03 -

Cathodic Protection Engineer

Current

China Petroleum Pipeline Engineering Company Ltd. , Fujairah, UAE

Started working as a Cathodic Protection Engineer in M Project of ADNOC in Fujairah City.

2018-03 -2020-02

Cathodic Protection Engineer

Corrtech International Pvt. Ltd., Ahmedabad, India, Gujarat

- Execution of Cathodic Protection projects at from Head Office.
- Documentation work related to CP activities.
- Channelizing resources and equipment towards most optimal use.
- Preparing project schedule, budgeting and monitoring activities on routine basis.
- Conducting frequent site visits to ensure project specific activities in line with the approved documents.
- Maintaining proper client interaction and services.
- Preparing payment invoicing terms with contractors and clients.
- Compliance of HR, safety and statutory measures at sites.
- Ensuring customer compliance in terms of quality and timelines.
- Design and execution of corrosion control program to

Inspection Excellent Invoicing Excellent Mail Excellent Project Design Excellent Quality assurance Excellent Safety Excellent Testing & Commissioning Excellent **Software** MS Office Excellent Languages English Superior Bengali **Native** Hindi

- protect assets and ensure continuity of operations.
- Planning and execution of condition monitoring and predictive maintenance plans
- Root cause analysis of fixed equipment failure and recommendation of remedial actions
- Familiarization with Inspection techniques such as Visual inspection, , Cathodic Protection and Holiday detection
- Review of damage mechanisms, consequences of failure, and inspection plans
- Quality control and Quality assurance of coating repair jobs
- Ensuring process safety and risk management objectives by participation in Management of
- Change (MOC), Process Hazard Analysis (PHA) and Pre-Startup Safety Reviews (PSSR)
- Understanding of Work permit system, Emergency response procedures, Lifesaving equipment & Firefighting methods
- Familiar with engineering standards of NACE, API, ASME, ASTM
- Preparation of departmental budget forecasts, overall cost management of a project.
- Preparation of purchase specifications
- Preparation of scope of work and scope clarifications
- Material/Vendor selection, evaluation of prices, preparation of purchase orders in consultation with corporate services department
- Spares balance investigation and inventory management of all spares of corrosion protection equipment

Project Details:

Detailed Design Engineering, Supply, Installation,
Testing and Commissioning for 3 nos.
Underground Vessel in CPCL Chennai Manali
Refinery

<u>Client</u>: Chennai Petroleum Corporation Limited

Consultant: Engineers India Limited

Contractor: Bridge and Roof India Limited

Detailed Design Engineering, Supply, Installation,
Testing and Commissioning for 1 CBD Vessel in
BORL Bina Refinery

<u>Client</u>: Bharat Oman Refineries Limited <u>Consultant</u>: Engineers India Limited

Detailed Design Engineering, Supply, Installation,
Testing and Commissioning for 1 CBD Vessel in
Assam Petrochemicals Limited, Namrup Site

<u>Client</u>: Assam Petrochemicals Limited <u>Consultant</u>: Engineers India Limited

Contractor: Powermax India Pvt. Limited

Monitoring and Maintenance of MMBPL and BKPL
Pipeline of BPCL

<u>Client</u>: Bharat Petroleum Corporation Limited

- AC Mitigation Works with Zn Ribbon Anodes and Solid State Device in Mundra-Delhi Pipeline, HPCL Client: Hindustan Petroleum Corporation Limited
- Supply, Installation, Testing and Commissioning of Permanent ICCP System for Ammonia 5 and Ammonia 1 Plant is RCFL Trombay Unit Client: Rashtriya Chemicals Fertilizers Limited
- Detailed Design Engineering, Supply, Installation, Testing and Commissioning of SACP and ICCP System for CFG3 Plants Project at Kota, Rajasthan, India

<u>Client</u>: Chambal Fertilizer and Chemicals Limited <u>Consultant</u>: Toyo Engineering India Private Limited 2018-02

German Cathodic Protection & Partners LLC, Muscat, Oman

Responsibilities include making project design, detailed engineering, Documentation, projects and material planning and site coordination. GCP has also provided me a good field experience in CP System Installation, Commissioning, Monitoring, Troubleshooting, and Surveys like On-OFF etc. by working in various project sites in Oman.

Project Details (Middle East):

 Quarterly Cathodic Protection System Monitoring & Survey in Mukhaizna Oil Field (Oxy South)

Client: Occidental Oman INC

 Line Current test posts Upgrading in Safah Oil Field (Oxy North)

Client: Occidental Oman INC

 Cathodic Protection Groundbed Installation at Lekhwair and Al-Barakah (Oxy North)

Client: Occidental Oman INC

 Provision For Cathodic Protection Maintenance **Activities in Oxy Safah Oil Field**

Client: Occidental Oman INC

 NGL Extraction Unit with Off Site works & Utilities (Package LPIC-EPC-3),Fahud,Oman Tank External Bottom Plate CP with MMO-Ti Ribbon Anode

Client : Orpic

Consultant: GS E&C

Contractor: Zawawi Powertech Engineering LLC

Project Engineer 2013-10 -

> Corrtech International Private Limited, Ahmedabad, India, Gujarat

2017-05

- Being an Electrical Engineer by graduation I started my career in Corrtech as a Cathodic Protection Engineer.
- Job responsibilities include site survey, attending progress meeting, optimizing resources, installation and commissioning, making as-built drawings and hand-over documents etc. Corrtech gave me the opportunity to learn CP technology that is an applied field of my graduation degree Electrical Engineering.

Project Details:

 Supply and installation of Cathodic Protection system for U/G Piping in Paradip Refinery

<u>Client</u>: Indian Oil Corporation Limited <u>Consultant</u>: Amec Foster Wheeler

 Cathodic Protection System for 5 Nos. Crude Oil Storage Tank at Indian Oil Corporation Limited PHBPL, Paradip

<u>Client</u>: Indian Oil Corporation Limited <u>Contractor</u>: Bridge & Roof India Limited

Cathodic Protection System for Paradip South
Jetty Pipeline Project, Paradip

<u>Client</u>: Indian Oil Corporation Limited <u>Consultant</u>: Engineers Indian Limited

Contractor: Fernas Construction India Private Limited

Coating Conductance Survey and Soil Resistivity
Survey of Vizag-Vijaywada-Secunderabad Pipeline
Client: Hindustan Petroleum Corporation Limited

Temporary and Permanent Cathodic Protection
System of Dahej-Nagothane Ethane Pipeline Project

<u>Client</u>: Reliance Gas Pipeline Limited <u>Consultant</u>: Sanmarg Projects Limited

Education

1996-05 - High School

2008-05 Hindu School - Kolkata, India

2009-08 - B.Tech: Electrical Engineering

St. Thomas College Of Engineering & Technology -

Kolkata, India

CGPA: 7.21

2017-01 - Cathodic Protection Technician (NACE CP-2)

National Association Of Corrosion Engineers -

Houston, USA

2020-01 - Cathodic Protection Technologist (NACE CP-3)

Certification ID: 67918

National Association Of Corrosion Engineers -

Houston, USA

Affiliations

Active member of National Association of Corrosion Engineers (NACE), Houston, USA,

Interests

Sports, Fitness, Travelling

Additional Information

I am sure that I could adapt myself to any kind of pursuit with all the training and innovative abilities, which I have refined in my career. Given an opportunity to be a part of your organization, I assure that my quality education blended with sense of responsibility shall enable me hone in on the goal of the organization. I do hereby confirm that the information furnished above is true to the best of my knowledge.